A Guide to the Great Falls Volunteer Fire Department Minutes, 1942-2005
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Great Falls Volunteer Fire Department Minutes, 1942-2005
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 05-46
2.0 linear feet
The Great Falls Volunteer Fire Department Minutes span the years 1942-2005 and contain minute books, loose minutes, and correspondence.
Great Falls Volunteer Fire Department
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Milburn Sanders, May 2011
Historical and Biographical Information
The Forestville Volunteer Fire Department was organized at the Great Falls Grange on May 4, 1942 as an auxiliary of the McLean Volunteer Fire Department. In October 1955, the name was changed to the Great Falls Volunteer Fire Department. Today, GVFD is designated as Company 412 by the Fairfax County Fire and Rescue Department.
Scope and Content
The Great Falls Volunteer Fire Department Minutes span the years 1942-2005 and contain minute books, loose minutes, and correspondence. The collection contains minutes of the general membership meetings of the fire department and the Board of Directors from May 4, 1942 through April 4, 2005. The majority of these minute books were recorded by Milburn Sanders, the recording secretary for the fire department.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Fire departments - Virginia - Fairfax County; Great Falls (Va.) - History; Great Falls Volunteer Fire Department; Sanders, Milburn P. (1922-2012)
Container List
- Minutes. May 4, 1942- Dec 7, 1942 (loose leaf), 1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Minute Book, January 4, 1943 - September 19, 1949, 1943-1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Minute Book, October 3, 1949 - February 2, 1953, 1949-1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Minute Book, March 2, 1953 - September 12, 1955, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Minute Book, October 3, 1955 - November 1, 1965, 1955-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Minute Book, December 6, 1965 - September 9, 1985, 1965-1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Minute Book, October 7, 1985 - December 17, 1990, 1985-1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Minute Book, January 7, 1991 - January 9, 1995, 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Minute Book, January 9, 1995 - January 5, 1998, 1995-1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Minute Book, January 5, 1998 - December 3, 2001, 1998-2001 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Minute Book, January 7, 2002 - August 4, 2003, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Minute Book, August 14, 2003 - April 4, 2005, 2003-2005 (Box 4, Folder 3)